

Contact

0428 176 421

timothy.long@live.com.au

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tfxlong/

Paddington, Brisbane

Foundational Skills

HTML CSS/SASS, RUBY

PYTHON, JAVASCRIPT

RUBY ON RAILS, REACT, EXPRESS

NODE.JS, MongoDB, SQL

Foundational Knowledge

HISTORY OF WEB DEVELOPMENT

ETHICS, LAWS & GUIDELINES

THREAT ACTORS (Nation State, Hacktivist, Cybercriminal)

THREAT VECTORS (malicious programming and social engineering)

RISK IMPLICATIONS & MANAGEMENT

DATABASE STRUCTURES Relational Schemas and Diagrams

TIMOTHY LONG

full stack developer (jnr)

Profile

Dedicated and hard-working father of four; with the maturity and experience to appreciate diverse work environments, and the quiet confidence of providing proven, above-expectation results for all previous employers.

Completing two qualifications has granted me a broad range of foundational skills in programming and a deeper understanding of cyber security, while still allowing flexibility to build further into the company's preferred technologies. I offer an attitude that rapidly attunes to a company's goals, pursuits and culture, a willingness to work hard, a desire to assist others, and the drive to perform at my best.

Education

Coder Academy

Diploma of Information Technology 2021-2022

- Introduction to the Web & Foundational Programming
- Programming I and II
- Information Systems and Discrete Mathematics
- Database Systems

University of Wollongong

Graduate Certificate in Cyber Security, 2021

- Python Programming for Cyber Security
- Cyber Security Risk and Risk Management
- Databases and Security
- Web Security

Courses

MichiganX

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

- Introduction to the concepts in programming languages
- Initial course resulting in continued learning

Python Data Structures

- Introduction to collections and file interaction
- Recognising concepts extensible to other languages

Microsoft DEV262x

Logic and Computational Thinking

- Introduction to logical constructions
- Adapting a logical mindset when programming

TIMOTHY LONG

Contact

+61 428 176 421

timothy.long@live.com.au

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tfxlong/

Paddington, Brisbane

References

Andrew Landale Managing Director Seed Solutions Australia

(02) 6060 4108 andrew@seedsolutions.com.au

> Dr Ben Hines Head of Exploration Dart Mining NL

0448 513 434 bhines@dartmining.com.au

Projects

Marketplace Application - "Surf-Swap" (Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS)

https://surf-swap-21.herokuapp.com

- Two-way marketplace with original concept
- Focus on frameworks and database integration
- Implementation of authentication and authorisation

Profile Webpage (HTML, CSS)

https://tfxl.github.io/

- Designing, project planning and use of wireframes
- In class presentations with preparation of slide deck
- Project implementation of semantic tags $\operatorname{\mathscr{C}}$ accessibility features

Terminal Project - "African Charity Challenge" (Ruby)

https://github.com/tfxlong/african_charity_challenge

- Interactive user interface in terminal
- Exploration of classes, control flow and file handling
- Utlisation of Ruby gems for enhanced features

Pygame - "Snakey Snake Snake" (Python)

https://github.com/tfxlong/snakey_snake_snake

- Creation of basic snake game with own features such as two-player
- Additional constraints including boundary option and direction control
- Implementation of modules, functions and classes

Encrypted Messaging (Cyber Security)

- Establish encrypted communication with basic GUI
- Creating and connecting socket connections
- Working with a complex set of instructions

Weekly Forum Contributions (Cyber Security)

- 3 formal discussion of recently learned concepts every week
- Additional research and summaries of topics expected
- Resource should be relevant and benefit other students

Work History

Manager (Warehouse/Operations)

Seed Solutions Australia | 2019 - 2021

- Ensuring plant operations meet rigorous quality standards
- Supervising and assisting staff in all operational matters
- Co-ordinating logistics, staffing and seed/grain testing

Geological Field Assistant

Dart Mining NL | 2017-2019

- Completing remote access exploration for minerals
- Assisting geologist in rock and soil sampling expeditions
- Completing XREF (x-ray) analysis and recording of field samples

TIMOTHY LONG

Contact

+61 428 176 421

timothy.long@live.com.au https://www.linkedin.com/in/tfxlong/

Paddington, Brisbane

Thank you for the opportunity to apply for this internship with your company. It is a privilege to be considered, and to demonstrate why I am a suitable candidate.

After several years investing in labour-intensive roles, I created the financial circumstances to dedicate my time to completing a Diploma of Information Technology with Coder Academy, and a Graduate Certificate of Cyber Security with the University of Wollongong. This has provided me with a solid range of theoretical foundational knowledge and industry relevant practice to start building a career pathway.

This decision will allow for a more creative and constructive career into the future, and will provide my growing family with an additional layer of stability above that which is afforded by agriculture or mining exploration. As an intern, and as with any other role, I am motivated to perform above expectations, to take seriously the responsibilities that I am assigned, and appreciate the opportunities that are offered.

It is a matter of pride that I have been recognised as a respectful and hard-working employee who can be relied on to go the extra mile, and who ensures I play my part towards the successes of the business.

Please do not hesitate to make contact if you would like any further information, or if I can be of assistance in any way, and thank you again for your consideration.

Kind Regards,

Timothy Long